(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T23:42:50.925504",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アスファルト タイヤを切りつけながら
While cutting the asphalt with tires,
暗闇 走りぬける
I run through the darkness.
チープなスリルに身をまかせても
Even if I surrender myself to a cheap thrill,
明日におびえていたよ
I was frightened of tomorrow.
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために生きられるなら
If I can live for someone else,
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
何もこわくはない
I'm not afraid of anything.
Get wild and tough
ひとりでは解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
holding a puzzle of love that cannot be solved alone.
Get wild and tough
この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
I don't want to rely on kindness in this city.
Get chance and luck
君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
there is surely something that only you can protect.
Get chance and luck
ひとりでも傷ついた夢をとりもどすよ
even if you are alone, you will recover your wounded dream.
Steppin' out
[Song: Steppin' out]
ありきたりな僕の 日々を壊してくれ
Please crush my ordinary days
異常なほどの刺激を 待ち望んでいたのかな
I wonder if I've been craving abnormal stimulation
ちょっとしたそんな冒険心は 改札に吸い込まれて
A dash of such adventurous spirit gets sucked into the ticket gate
吐き出されたどり着いた 雨降るこの街
Spat out, I arrived here in this rainy city
何も感じれないまま 死んでいくのは御免だ
I refuse to die numbly, without feeling anything
終わりのその先も目指して
Aiming for what lies beyond the end
駆け出せ steppin' out tonight
Let's run, stepping out tonight
僕らは不確かなまま
We remain uncertain
輝く steppin' out tonight
Shine on, stepping out tonight
待ってるんだぜ 明日が
Tomorrow is waiting for us
抗え steppin' out tonight
Resist, stepping out tonight
僕らは風の中
We are in the wind
それでも steppin' out tonight
Even so, stepping out tonight
追いかけてんだ so there's no looking back
I'm pursuing it, so there's no looking back
また首を突っ込んで
I stick my neck into it again
見事に散らかしてんだ
and make a glorious mess of it
曖昧で退屈な気持ちとおさらばさ
Saying goodbye to those vague, boring feelings
関係ないって顔したって どこかで繋がっていて
Even if you pretend you don't care, we're connected somewhere
何度だって引き戻すと 手招くこの街
This city beckons, pulling me back time and time again
ビリビリしびれるような 今を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in this thrilling moment
極限のギリギリで行こうぜ
Let's go to the extreme, right to the limit
駆け出せ steppin' out tonight
Let's run, stepping out tonight
僕らは不確かなまま
We remain uncertain
輝く steppin' out tonight
Shine on, stepping out tonight
待ってるんだぜ 明日が
Tomorrow is waiting for us
抗え steppin' out tonight
Resist, stepping out tonight
僕らは風の中
We are in the wind
それでも steppin' out tonight
Even so, stepping out tonight
追いかけてんだ so there's no looking back
I'm pursuing it, so there's no looking back
Yeah! Inside, outside...
Inside outside, I just wanna feel good everyday
いっさいがっさい I just want to feel alive
With everything, I just want to feel alive
駆け出せ steppin' out tonight
Let's run, stepping out tonight
僕らは不確かなまま
We remain uncertain
輝く steppin' out tonight
Shine on, stepping out tonight
待ってるんだぜ 明日が
Tomorrow is waiting for us
抗え steppin' out tonight
Resist, stepping out tonight
僕らは風の中
We are in the wind
それでも steppin' out tonight
Even so, stepping out tonight
追いかけてんだ so there's no looking back
I'm pursuing it, so there's no looking back
[A]ddiction
[Song: [A]ddiction]
Don't take your love away, we ain't heard nothing yet, yet
Don't take your love away, wake up, make up, bang
また鳴り出した表示は あなた「今忙しいの」
The display lights up again, saying you're "busy right now"
未読のトークと love call もいっぱいで忙しない「邪魔をしないで頂戴」
Unread chats and love calls piled up, "please don't bother me"
突き返す拗ねくれた可愛気ないセリフ
A cold, unyielding, unlovely reply
なんてまだガキね
How childish of you.
本音は言わない
You won't show your true feelings.
嫌い？　やましい？
Do you hate me? Are you feeling guilty?
甘い言葉かけるよりも　ずっと愛おしい
That's far more darling than whispering sweet words.
たまらなくなるほど　求めて離さないで
Want me so much you can't stand it, and don't let me go.
キスじゃ足りなくて　いっそ殺して
A kiss is not enough, just kill me instead.
Predilection　貴方を手にかけて
Predilection, getting my hands on you...
Infatuation　呼吸さえ止めて保存
Infatuation, even stopping your breath...
Dedication　このままAddictionして　まだ足りない　一口で終い
Dedication, getting addicted just like this... It's still not enough, done in one bite.
Predilection　甘く口をつけて
Predilection, placing my lips so sweetly...
Infatuation　そのまま飲み込んで
Infatuation, swallow it whole just like that...
Dedication　すぐさまAddictionして　ほら足りない　一口死ぬほど愛したいから
Dedication, instantly getting addicted... Look, it's not enough, I want to love you to death in one bite.
Don't think you'll love her way, we hit it up and get yet
Don't think you'll love her way, wake up, make up, bang bang!
Uhh Habitと愛情　語って良い　貴方には私しかいない
Uhh, you can talk about habits and affection, but you only have me.
Uhh Ticketと愛情が足りないわ　私には貴方しかいないなんて
Uhh, I don't have enough tickets or affection, to say you are the only one for me.
信じて外した　この手掴んだ　まだ未練があるの？ねえ甘ったるい
I believed and let go, but grasped this hand. Do you still have regrets? How sweet.
わがまま　愛と名付けて　私排する
Naming selfishness as "love", I reject it.
貴方に溺れてく　息苦しいくらいに
I'm drowning in you, to the point of suffocating.
深酔いさせて　いっそ殺して
Let me get deeply drunk, just kill me instead.
Predilection　私を手にかけて
Predilection, getting your hands on me...
Infatuation　キスで口塞いで保存
Infatuation, block my mouth with a kiss...
Dedication　まだまだAddictionして　まだ足りない　非合理的な愛
Dedication, getting addicted more and more... Still not enough, this irrational love.
Predilection　毒々しく流し込んで
Predilection, pouring it in poisonously...
Infatuation　躊躇いなど捨てて
Infatuation, cast aside all hesitation...
Dedication　すぐさまAddictionして　ほら足りない　一口これで終わらせないで
Dedication, instantly getting addicted... Look, it's not enough, don't let it end with one bite.
My love, my love, continue to further evolve more. My love, my love, is decided with you!
Your love, your love, continue to further evolve more, more, more. Yes, I'm a little confused.
これはあんたのせい？　あんたがどうしても私に
Is this your fault? No matter how much you want to...
触れたいのはただ愛されたかっただけだったの私以外
touch me, did you just want to be loved by someone other than me?
いらないそういう言葉は期待するだけ無駄って
I don't need those words, I've learned that expecting...
知ってしまった　愛しかわからないよね
anything is useless. We only understand love, right?
たまらなくなるほど　求めて離さないで
Want me so much you can't stand it, and don't let me go.
キスじゃ足りなくて　いっそ殺して
A kiss is not enough, just kill me instead.
Predilection　貴方を手にかけて
Predilection, getting my hands on you...
Infatuation　呼吸さえ止めて保存
Infatuation, even stopping your breath...
Dedication　このままAddictionして　まだ足りない　一口で終い
Dedication, getting addicted just like this... It's still not enough, done in one bite.
Predilection　甘く口をつけて
Predilection, placing my lips so sweetly...
Infatuation　そのまま飲み込んで保存
Infatuation, swallow it whole just like that...
Dedication　すぐさまAddictionして　サヨナラなんか吐き出しで息が止まるのよ今
Dedication, instantly getting addicted... Spitting out "goodbyes", my breath stops right now.
It's not a game
I'm not a robot A.I. challenging you
I'm not a phantom
I'm in your face and
I'm here to see it through
Right before your eyes
Watch us multiply
Come to claim our rights - it's time
As our power grows
Tryin' to stop us shows
Might as well go try'n stop time
So you know that we're out there
Swatting lies in the making
...can't move fast without breaking
Can't hold on or life won't change
And our voices ring out, yeah
Took the mask off to feel free
Fought it out in the debris
Now we know that life will change
Ain't it a shame
I'm not a figment of your ailing old mind
I'm just as real as, I'm just as dangerous
As you, so know you'll find
A taste of your own meds
Fire in every breath
Fire inside your head, your heart
And as your crippled brain
Tries to fight in vain
Your empire will fall...
...apart
And you'll know we were out there
Swatted lies in the making
Your empire for the taking
Can't hold on or life won't change
And our voices ring out, here
Took the mask off to feel free
Fought it out in the debris
Now we know that life will change
X-encounter
Lyrics: 黒崎真音 Music: 高瀬一矢
[Title: X-encounter]
[Lyrics: Maon Kurosaki / Music: Kazuya Takase]
飛べない... ここからじゃ
I can't fly... not from here.
横顔 眺めてるだけじゃ
Just by staring at your profile,
無力さを 嘆いても
even if I lament my helplessness,
この背を 誰も押さない
no one will push my back.
Going out!
飛び方を忘れていた
I had forgotten how to fly...
闇鴉たちの 嘆きのvoice
...the grieving voices of the crows.
凍てつく 無機質な 世界に
In this freezing, inorganic world,
何を望むの?
what do you hope for?
そう だけどね 確実な
That's true, but a certain...
希望が もう僕の中に
...hope is already inside of me.
Going up!
「何が出来るか」なんてもう やってみなきゃ ワカラナイ
"What I can do" is something I won't know until I try!
走り出した 序章(はじまり)へ
Running towards the beginning prologue...
きっと生まれる前から 決まっていた
...surely decided before I was even born.
羽根を揺らし 強く地を蹴って
Fluttering my wings, kicking off the ground hard,
キミの元へ
I'll head to your side.
羽撃たく "RAVENS!"
Soar, RAVENS!
Fight! keep holding on!
何千の ループの中 出逢う この現世(ばしょ)で
Meeting in this world after thousands of loops,
もう止められない 宿命(カルマ)の真下で
underneath a karma we can no longer stop,
僕に出来ること がどんなに僅かでも
no matter how little I can do,
その体に背負うもの
the burden you bear on your body...
その痛み 分け合える日まで
...until the day we can share that pain,
キミの傍にいるよ
I will be by your side.
のよう 飛び立つ今 恐れず
I will fly away now, without fear...
モーションに 振り回されず
Without being swayed by mere illusions,
自分の居場所 探して
I'm searching for my own place.
後悔に なぞらえた
Likened to regret,
モノクロームの世界 縛り付く夜にいた
I was in a monochrome world, bound to the night.
うつむくように 風に揺れて
Swaying in the wind as if looking down,
僕はまだ 弱いままで
I'm still weak...
迷って 壊れたら
If I get lost and break,
そうやって続く世界で
in this world that continues on that way...
たった一つ 見つけたら
If I can find just one thing,
瞬く星を描き 進め
I will draw a twinkling star and move forward.
闇から 覗いた光
A light peeking through the darkness...
手を伸ばして さあ行こう
Reach out your hand, let's go!
走り出した この想い ほら
These feelings have started running, look!
ココロの羅針盤が 導いて
The compass in my heart is guiding me.
染みついている 癒えない傷も
Even the unhealing wounds that stain me...
この翼で 運んでいくウェイブ
I will carry them away on these wings... Wave!
I keep holding on!
空を切り カタチのない涙も蹴散らして
Cutting through the air, kicking away even shapeless tears,
凛とした目に 宿る灯火を
The light dwelling in your dignified eyes...
曇らせるはずはない
There's no way it will be clouded.
君はそのままでいて
Please stay just the way you are.
向かい風に逆らい
Against the headwind,
地に立ち 羽広げ 目指そう僕ら
standing on the ground, spreading our wings, let's aim high,
果てる日まで ともに駆けて
running together until our final day,
ゆこう
let's go!
誰のせいでもない涙
Tears that are no one's fault,
誇りにして さあ行こう
take pride in them, and let's go!
走り出そう 始まりへ
Let's start running toward the beginning.
きっと生まれる前から 決まっていた
It was surely decided even before we were born.
羽を揺らし 強く地を蹴って
Flapping our wings, kicking off the ground strongly,
君のもとへ 羽ばたこうウェーブ
I'll flap my wings to you... Wave!
I keep holding on!
何度でも 後悔のあとに息づく鼓動
No matter how many times, the heartbeat breathing after regret...
この一瞬が 永遠へと変わる
This moment turns into eternity.
手を繋ぎ そして 世界を見に行こう
Let's hold hands and go see the world.
皮肉にも僕たちは
Ironically, we...
永い夜をくぐり抜けて
will pass through the long night,
知るんだろう
and surely we will learn...
強さの意味を
...the meaning of strength.
真実へと 駆けてゆこう
Let's run toward the truth.
遠回り それはきっと
Taking a detour, that surely...
どんな景色にも 愛を持って<
With love for any scenery,
立つときに 世界はまた 生まれ変わる
when we stand, the world will be reborn once again!
Yeah! Haha!
Thank you so much for watching the anniversary!
So far! Are you guys having a good time?
Don't forget to share your comments using the...
...hashtag shown at the top right of the screen!
Hashtag Promise to...
Oh, this way! This way!
This way! No, this way!
This way, this way, this way! Hashtag Promise to you!
All right, we're currently at the Promise Hideout!
Over there.
Whoa! Oh my god, that is huge!
I know, right? Oh my god, it's so pretty!
We're so... I got way too excited.
No, you got... don't die! Don't die! Don't die!
It's so big. Hello!
Is there a helicopter flying out there taking videos of us?
Now we have it. And now that we also have such a fancy stage on the rooftop as well and everything...
...let's turn things up with some fun variety games!
Variety games? Yes, it's a variety part. Oh my god!
Yeah. I bet you guys are probably feeling a bit tired after that intense first half of this live, right?
I'm good! I'm there, I'm alive, I'm standing. So we're... we're good!
Yeah, you guys seem a little tired. Yeah.
To help you recover from that fatigue and tiredness, I've prepared the perfect segment for you guys.
Oh? Oh...
Yes, it's called... Pleasure or Pain? Promise Foot Massage Karaoke Battle!
But what does that mean? Did she say feet?
Each of us will sing one chorus from two songs they're good at!
Yes! We'll use the karaoke machine scoring system...
...and the person with the highest combined score will win!
There's also a twist?
Yes! We will be singing while receiving foot massages!
Wait, what?!
And how that will affect our performance or score... well, we'll see and find out together!
Right here? Oh, oh, yay. Yes!
And there'll be a punishment for the losers as well, of course.
Two losers, I'm pretty sure that's how it is, yeah. Okay.
And as for the punishment, the losers will have to drink this...
...super sour geki-suppa drink!
Geki-suppa juice. A what? Geki-suppa juice. Whoa!
Now, let me show you the key item that could make or break this battle. Here's what we'll use for the first round!
Ta-da!
It's a foot reflexology mat!
I've never stepped on one of these before. I have. Oh, it's not pleasant. It's not fun. Yeah, never.
Wait, so you want us to... wait, wait, we're singing while we're on this? We have to walk on this.
Yeah, you're going to sound amazing. We're all going to sound amazing singing on this, yes.
So, who's brave enough to go first?
Senpai! Senpai? Senpai! Senpai!
I feel like... You look so beautiful today! Yeah, yeah.
That's not going to come out from complimenting me. Oh, you look, you look so amazing, oh my god!
But, you know, I feel like as a senpai, you should show us how it's done, right?
Fine, I'll go first, okay? Fine. Yay! I'll show you how it's done. Yes! Let's go!
All right, so IRyS, which song are you going to sing?
I am going to sing... Zankyou Sanka! Ooh, Zankyou Sanka. Yes.
If you're ready, jump on the mat! Yes!
Get on the mat! Get on the mat! Get on the mat!
Oh! Oh, it hurts! Oh, it hurts!
Oh, are you okay? Are you okay? Music, please! It's not so bad. Yes, you do.
Oh! It's starting! Let's go! I know, it's...
Ah! Oh my god! Keep walking! Keep walking!
Oh, it hurts! It hurts!
誰が袖に咲く幻花 ただそこに藍を落とした
Who is the phantom flower that blooms on the sleeve? I just dropped my indigo dye over there
派手に色を溶かす夜に 銀朱の月を添えて
On a night when the colors dissolve gaudily, with the moon of silver vermilion
転がるように風を切って 躓くごとに強くなった
I cut through the wind as if rolling, getting stronger with every stumble
光も痛みも怒りも全部 抱きしめて
I embrace all of the light, the pain, and the anger
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If I'm not chosen, I'll just choose for myself
声よ 轟け 夜のその向こうへ 涙で滲んでた
Let my voice roar out beyond the night, which was blurred with my tears
あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡れ
Let it reverberate all the way to that far-off landscape
何を奏でて？ 誰に届けたくて？ 不確かなままでいい
What am I playing? Who do I want to reach? It's fine to be uncertain
どんなに暗い感情も どんなに長い葛藤も 歌と散れ 残響
No matter how dark the feelings, no matter how long the conflict, scatter like a song, reverberation
痛い！痛い！痛い！
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
I can barely balance!
You need a good rub, right? Good. There you go.
Oh my god, that hurt.
How's your blood flow? Do you feel...
How do you... do you feel refreshed?
You look great. All right, looks like the score is in.
Shall we see the score? Hi! This is what she got!
Ta-da!
I've never gotten a score that low before.
70.161! That's good! That's good!
That's good? What are you talking about?
You know, 70, that's a... that's a... that's a C. No, B.
That's a B. That's a B minus.
B minus. B minus.
B minus? That's a C, that's a C minus.
No, no, no... It's B minus.
Alrighty then. Who wants to go next?
Senpai! Senpai! Oh, senpai ja nai.
Senpai! Senpai! Oh, she's not our senpai.
We're from... We're from the same...
She's senpai by two hours. Was it two hours?
Yeah, I think it was around two hours. Senpai by two hours!
I've never heard that from you before. Okay, I guess...
I'll go. It's gonna be so much fun.
Okay, so Kronii, what song are you gonna sing for us?
Uh, I'm gonna be singing "Mousou Zei".
Wow! Mucho mucho, Mousou Zei.
Yeah, cuz... I only know old songs, yay!
That's great, I know that song!
Okay then. All right, please...
Start the music! Music, start-o!
Uh-oh. Okay.
She sounds like she's confused.
We're gonna be fine, we're gonna be fine.
あの子もいいな あの子もいいな
That girl is nice, that girl is nice too
頭の中でイイコトしてる
Having pleasant thoughts inside my head
あなたはそれで満足ですか？
Are you satisfied with that?
叶えたいとは思いませんか？
Don't you want to make it come true?
You're on a good spot right now. You're doing good.
She's fine, yeah, all right.
あの子でいいや あの子でいいや
That girl will do, that girl will do
妥協大好き 飲む針千本
I love compromising, swallowing a thousand needles
あなたはそれで満足ですか？
Are you satisfied with that?
叶えたいとは思いませんか？
Don't you want to make it come true?
納めましょう妄想税
Let's pay the delusional tax
皆様の暮らしを豊かにするために
To enrich everyone's lives
叶えたいを現実に
Turn your wishes into reality
今、未来を買い戻せ
Now, buy back the future
アレしたい病も 欲しがりも
The "wanting to do that" disease, and greeds too
さぁ、痛いのその向こうへ
Now, beyond the pain
そう、汚い妄想は
Yes, dirty delusions
汚いお金で解決させましょう
Let's resolve them with dirty money
yeah!?
Yeah! Yay! You did amazing!
I feel like that brought out like a... like a roughness.
Whoa! Did you actually sing on that?
Oh, wow, blood circulation.
That's a lot of blood circulation. Wow.
All right, the score is in. Let's see what Kronii got.
Yay!
Wait, wait, it's still first half. I can still make it.
Still first half. All right, I'll go, my turn!
Yeah! Let's go! Yay!
I'm excited. I've been wanting to sing this song for so long.
Okay, what song is it? What are you singing?
Fairy Tail! Yakusoku no Hi!
Finally, I finally found an instrumental track. I'm so excited.
To your childhood, I'm assuming? Not really, not really.
Okay, not a fairy tale... Now that you're ready, please hop onto...
The foot reflexology mat.
Come on, yes, ready? You ready?
Yeah! Okay, now please start singing. Music, start-o!
フェアリーテイル この手で 掴んだ 光は
Fairy Tail, the light I grasped with this hand
She's walking, she's walking! Ah!
You're great! Yeah, let's go! Dance, dance, dance!
夢に描いた理想郷 夢のまま終わらせない
The utopia I dreamed of, I won't let it end as just a dream
いつか会える 未来の僕に伝えたい
I want to tell my future self, whom I'll meet someday
時に未来は残酷で 鏡のように割れるけど
Sometimes the future is cruel, and it shatters like a mirror
欠片を失くさないよう 見つけ出せばいい
As long as we find the fragments so we don't lose them
凍える闇が
Even if the freezing darkness...
僕たちの行く手塞いでも きっと忘れない 希望
...blocks our path, I will surely not forget our hope
フェアリーテイル この手で掴んだ光は
Fairy Tail, the light I grasped with this hand
絆の力溢れているから
Because it overflows with the power of our bonds
溢れているから
...because they are overflowing...
だから
So,
僕らは
we...
知っている
...know...
悲しい
...those sad...
涙を
...tears.
だから譲れない
So I won't give in,
揺るがない
I won't waver.
夢見たあの日に
To that day I dreamed of,
そう
yes,
辿り着くまで
until I finally reach it!
Yeah! You guys can sing on this thing?
It brings out something...
...something from deep within.
From within? Okay, then.
Since you have something deep within, it's time to see what score that brought you! Hi...
81.434! / Whoa! / Yeah!
Wow, she got an 81.434 points!
Currently in first place is Hakos Baelz...
...with 81.434 points!
Any comments heading into the second half now?
I'm excited!
I'll continue to do my best...
...so that I don't have to do the juice!
Go on, then! Ganbarimasu!
Go on, then! I'll do my best!
Alrighty then, let me introduce the next key item...
...or should I say person, for the second half...
...in this foot massage battle, yeah?
では、お入りください！どうぞ！
Now, please come in! Come on!
こんにちは。 / こんにちは。
Hello. / Hello.
Okay, let me introduce you guys to Takita-san...
...who will be giving us foot massages, a foot massage pro!
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
怖い。 / 怖いね。
Scary. / It's scary, isn't it?
Are you excited?
痛いですか？ / 痛いです。
Does it hurt? / Yes, it hurts.
Okay, since it's going to hurt, who wants to kick things off?
Alright, since I went last last time, I'll go first this time.
That is right. That is true. What are you going to sing?
I'm going to be singing... Bakamitai!
行きます！
Here I go!
Okay then, please get ready. 滝田さんもよろしくお願いします！
Okay then, please get ready. Takita-san, please go ahead!
優しくしてください。
Please be gentle.
怖い！大丈夫、健康にいいんだから。 It's good for your health.
Scary! It's okay, it's good for your health. It's good for your health.
Let's go! / はい。
Let's go! / Yes.
Okay then, please start! Music start!
Inner peace...
Hi, inner peace...
馬鹿みたい 子供なのね
I'm a fool, just like a child...
夢を追って傷ついて
...chasing dreams and getting hurt.
嘘が下手なくせに
Even though you're terrible at lying...
笑えない笑顔みせた
...you showed me a joyless smile.
I love youも
Even "I love you"...
ろくに言わない
...you barely even said.
口下手で
So quiet...
ほんまに不器用
...and truly clumsy.
なのに なのにどうして
Yet, yet why...
サヨナラは言えたの
...were you able to say goodbye?
だめだね だめよ だめなのよ
It's no good, no good, it's just no use.
あんたが好きで好きすぎて
I love you, I love you way too much.
どれだけ
No matter how...
強いお酒でも
...strong the drink...
歪まない思い出が
...these memories won't blur.
馬鹿みたい
I've been a fool.
痛い！先生、先生、先生！ありがとうございます！
It hurts! Teacher, teacher, teacher! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます…
Thank you very much...
Oh, that was a beautiful ending to that song.
That's scary. Oh my god.
Alrighty! How was that?
How was the song while getting a foot massage, yeah?
I can't feel my big toes.
Now the score is in. Let's see what you got!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
You got a 68.057!
That's over 50. So close to a good number, yeah.
It's a pass. It's a pass. ありがとうございます。
It's a pass. It's a pass. Thank you very much.
You became healthy. You became a bit healthier.
A lot healthier.
Is it really that bad? Oh my god!
You're not exaggerating, are you?
大げさじゃない！やってよ！
I'm not exaggerating! You try it!
I want to. I want to try.
Okay, go! Before you sit, what are you going to sing?
うっせぇわを歌います！
I'm going to sing Usseewa!
よし、準備を。滝田様、またよろしくお願いします。
All righty, please get ready. Mr. Takita, please take care of us again.
よろしくお願いします。
Please take care of me.
ガチ痛い！ガチ痛い！
It really hurts! It really hurts!
うーん、無理かも…
I'm not able to...
終わったよ、終わった！心配しないで！
You're done, you're done! You don't have to worry!
イェーイ！オッケー！レッツゴー！
Yay! Okay then. Let's go!
ミュージック・スタート！
Music, start!
そんなに痛いのかな。/ 思い切りやっちゃって！
I wonder if it's going to be that bad. / Just go for it!
正しさとは 愚かさとは
What is right? What is foolishness?
それが何か見せつけてやる
I will show you what they are!
おお！上手い！上手い！
Oh! She sings well! She sings well!
徐々に温まってきてるね。
She's slowly warming up.
おお、すごい！
Oh, wow!
ちっちゃな頃から優等生 気づいたら大人になっていた
I've been an honor student since I was a little girl, and before I knew it, I was a grown-up.
ナイフの様な思考回路 持ち合わせる訳もなく
With no such thing as a knife-like thinking process.
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない 困っちまうこれは誰かのせい
But I'm not playing enough, something's missing, I'm in trouble, is this someone's fault?
あてもなくただ混乱するエイディ
With no direction, just a confused heyday.
それもそっか 最新の流行は当然の把握 経済の動向も通勤時チェック
I guess that's true. Keeping up with the latest fads is a given. Checking the economy on my commute, too.
純情な精神で入社しワーク 社会人じゃ当然のルールです
Joining the company with a pure spirit and working. It's a natural rule for working adults.
はぁ？
What?
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ あなたが思うより健康です
Shut up, shut up, shut up. I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸な あなたじゃ分からないかもね
Maybe you, who are mediocre in every way, wouldn't understand.
嗚呼よく似合う その可もなく不可もないメロディー
Ah, it suits you so well, that melody that is neither good nor bad.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ 頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
Shut up, shut up, shut up. We are built differently, so there's no problem.
すごーい！
Amazing!
マッサージされてるみたいね。
It looks like you're getting a massage.
気持ちよかった！イェーイ！
I feel so good! Yay!
え、マジで？は？
Eh, seriously? What?
それでは結果が出ました。何点だったか見てみましょう。結果をお願いします！
All right then, the score's in again. Let's see what you got. Result please!
ジャジャーン！
Jajan!
イェーイ！77.994点！
Yay! She got 77.994!
ほぼ78点じゃん！すごすぎる。
That's literally a 78! That's so good.
さて、次は…誰が残ってる？
All right, well... Who's left?
残るは一人だけ。アイリス、来なさい！
We only have one person left. IRyS, get over here!
はい…はい… / 早く行きなさい。何歌うの？
Yes... yes... / Go quickly. What song are you singing?
悪魔の子を歌います。世界はそれだけ残酷だから。
I am going to be singing Akuma no Ko because the world is just that cruel.
世界は残酷です。
The world is cruel.
先生、今度こそ本気でやってください！
Sir, please give it your all this time!
優しくしてください。 / 優しく？強く！
Please be gentle. / Gentle? Go strong!
強く！ / 強く。
Strong! / Strong.
よし、準備はいい？ / 怖いよ。
All right, you ready? / I'm scared.
よし、じゃあミュージック・スタート！
All right then, music, start!
ああ、心臓がバクバクする。
Oh my, my heart is beating.
鉄の弾が 正義の証明 貫けば 英雄に近づいた
An iron bullet is proof of justice. If it penetrates, you are closer to a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば 同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
If you close your eyes and touch it, you'll find a devil of the same shape and temperature.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの？ そこに壁があっただけなのに
I'm no good, but he is? Even though there was just a wall there.
生まれてしまった 運命嘆くな 僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Don't lament the fate you were born into, because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽があれば どこへだって行けるけど
If we had wings like birds, we could go anywhere, but...
帰る場所が なければ きっとどこへも行けない
If there's no place to return to, we surely can't go anywhere.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I hate to just live.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それでも君を愛すよ
But I still love you.
なにを犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しきとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is believing strongly in yourself.
痛い！
Ouch!
どうだった？気分はどう？
How was... how do you feel?
どう、スッキリした？スッキリしたでしょ？
How was it? Refreshing? Refreshing, right?
最高でした！
It was great!
素晴らしい体験でした。痛かったけど。
A wonderful experience. It hurt.
よし、結果が出たみたい。見てみようか。
All right, I feel like the scores are in. Shall we see?
ジャジャーン！
Jajan!
おお！すごい！
Oh! Wow!
すっごい！77.716点！
So good! 77.716!
ということで後半戦は終了！
And that concludes the second half!
親指がまだめちゃくちゃ痛い。
My big toe still hurts so bad.
うん、わかる。みんな痛がってたよね。
Yes, I know. Everyone was in pain.
滝田さん、ありがとうございました！
Mr. Takita, thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
痛気持ちよかったです。バイバイ！ありがとうございました！
It felt painfully good. Bye bye! Thank you very much!
Okay then!
I present to you the final scores!
The one and only first place...
...with 151.858 points is...
...Ouro Kronii!
Yeah!
Oh, a shoulder massage!
How do you feel? How do you feel?
Oh, I wish I got a massage for my left side too.
That would have been so nice.
But you know, I'm so happy...
...that we got to suffer together!
Yeah! Yay!
Okay, now with that wholesome moment aside...
Yeah, let's get back to the live!
No, not yet. Not yet.
Actually, let's get back to the live! We should get back to the live!
Yeah, I think it's time, yeah?
It's time for the punishment game!
Staff-san, please prepare. Thank you, thank you.
Okay, so they said it was like a super sour drink?
Yeah, I heard it's a sour drink.
It smells... It smells healthy.
Oh wait, it smells good though! It smells like ass.
It's like, plum, like ume maybe? Is it ume?
It smells ume-y. Yeah.
なんか臭くない？ちょっと…
Doesn't it smell bad? A bit...
じゃ、不健康の二人で。
Well, cheers to the two unhealthy ones.
はい。
Okay.
乾杯！
Cheers!
That tastes wonderful!
うめえ！
Delicious!
That's actually really good. Really? Wow.
酸っぱ！あ…
Sour! Ask...
You're having a great time!
It tastes better after a bit more time...
Oh! My face is turning into that lemon meme!
You know, the face just inverts.
ごちそうさまです。
Thank you for the drink.
But it's probably healthy.
Healthy, guys! That's clean! Woo!
Okay, so we're going to return to the live performance...
...and the second half includes new songs!
So let's keep it going, guys! Woo!
Let's go, babies!
Alright, you guys are fun. Okay, let's get a move on.
Let's get a move on.
Alright. Okay.
Still, we really have time now.
だいぶ良くなったよ。
I feel much better now.
全部全部アンタのせいだ
It's all, all your fault.
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
You're such a pain, it makes me wanna hurl.
何かに縋って諂って
Clinging to things, fawning over things...
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was stupid to think I'd get something out of it.
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
I'm a people-pleaser,
それ故にアンチの一生 gimme
so gimme a hater life.
浅いキャパシティ まいどおおきに
I've got a shallow capacity, thanks for your patronage.
つまるどこ人生ずっと地味
Basically, my life's always been drab.
「憎らしい！」「痛々しい！」
"How hateful! How pathetic!"
無視出来ないのが一層
The way I can't ignore you makes it worse—
腹立たしぃ 苛立たしぃ
How maddening, how vexing.
そろそろ飽きた自画自賛に
I've had just about enough of blowing my own horn.
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of "like" is apathy
≒繋がれた証
≒ proof that you're connected.
切り離せない関係
A relationship I can't cut off...
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I'd love to just look away from it.
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is what you'd call hate speech.
匿名性の声明を生命に載せてんだ
We're posting these anonymous declarations onto our very lives.
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度に癇癪
We spasm every time those ceaseless sirens draw near.
赤信号にずっと従順です。
We've obeyed red lights all this time.
大体アナタのコトアタシ
Point is, I absolutely—
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
—hate hate hate hate hate you.
omg 情けない最早
omg, how pathetic, I just wanna say—
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
—bye bye bye bye bye already.
脳内も予測不能故に
Can't tell what's going on in that mind, and thus there's—
解解解解解は無い
—no no no no no solution.
どうだい？アタシのコトアナタ
How's it? Do you absolutely—
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
—hate hate hate hate me now?
あぁ百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all pain and no gain, nothing, not see.
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
It'd be like nicotine to think back on the what-ifs.
i miss youって近付いた結末は
Going back because I missed you was a
凡ミス凡ミス
stupid mistake, mistake.
センキュー反面教師
Thanks for being a great bad example.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
You've left an aftertaste that won't ever disappear.
よせよせいい子ね
There, there, what a good girl.
笑顔振り撒きパラパラいい子ね
Strewing your smile around, scatter scatter, what a good girl.
だけどだけどその本性は？
But you know, but you know, what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？笑
Can you even tell right from wrong? (lol)
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Shrouded by an environment that traps people with demerits.
生涯、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞こえないわ！って
"Ow! Ow! Ow!" you cry, "but no one asks!" you'll say for life,
当然の報いにクラッちゃった
but—serves you right.
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors.
実のところ依存は両辺です
The truth is, it's codependence.
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if you shut it all down, it still sticks around.
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My weakness feels so cowardly.
全部全部アンタのせいで
It's all, all your fault I say.
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
It won't stop, it makes me wanna hurl.
...もないわ
...there's no going back.
いっそのこと切り離した方がラクなのにね
It'd be easier to just cut it off...
だいたいあなたのこと私 ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
Basically, I hate, hate, hate, hate, hate you!
お前が情けないもはや バイバイバイバイバイバイサヨナラ
You're so pathetic, it's already bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, goodbye!
脳内もう予測のゆえに カイカイカイカイカイカイワナイ
With my mind predicting everything, we don't even talk, talk, talk, talk, talk anymore!
そう、私のことあなた ダイダイダイダイダイキライ になるのかな？
And so, you hate, hate, hate, hate, hate me too, right? Or will you?
あー、傷つけ合って一丁前だね
Ah, hurting each other makes us look grown-up, doesn't it?
もしももしももしも、があれば 並んで歩いてニコイチだし
If, if, if only there was a "what if," we'd walk side-by-side as a perfect pair.
あー、満ちて欠けて気がついて 結末はボミボミボミ
Ah, waxing and waning, I realize the ending is just vomit, vomit, vomit.
サンキューは免疫、あと味一生消えてくれないわ
Saying thank you is immunity, but the aftertaste won't disappear for life!
Oh, uh-huh
Yeah, yeah
Yeah
I'm not into relationships.
I'm the relationship.
H - A - L - F
簡単な英語しかわかんない
I only understand simple English
踊るの大好き 健康第一
I love to dance, and health comes first
憧れとコンプレックス 大渋滞
A massive traffic jam of admiration and complexes
カーステでノリノリ カーストは飽き飽き
Rocking to the car stereo, totally tired of the caste system
試されてる いつもいつでも
We're being tested, always and forever
恵まれてるかどうかを
On whether we're blessed or not
楽しくしていたい 泣きたくないから
I just want to have fun, because I don't want to cry
問いだだす 神さまがいなくても
I'll keep questioning, even if God isn't there
もうカッコつけてくしかないじゃん
I've got no choice but to keep acting cool!
そのまま このまま 降り注ぐひかり
Just like that, just like this, the light pours down on us
ねえ 半分なんて思ったことないぜ
Hey, I've never once thought of myself as just "half"!
このまま そのまま 突き進むひかり
Just like this, just like that, the light charges ahead!
いじわるなんかじゃ止まんない
Some mean-spiritedness won't stop me
笑わせたいのに 上手に出来ない
I want to make you laugh, but I can't do it well
誰かのせいにはしたくないよ
I don't want to blame it on anyone else
生まれてみたいから生まれて来ただけ
I just came here because I wanted to experience being born
あたらしい普通としあわせ
A new kind of normal and happiness...
そんなに遠くはないでしょう
...can't be that far away, can it?
それでもいまも誰かが 撃ち放つ かなしみと怒りの
Even so, even now, someone is unleashing sadness and anger...
H - A - L - F
損をしたり ちょっとつらい
Suffering losses can be a little tough
そんな日もあるけれど
There are days like that, too
いばらの道で 花が咲くなら
But if flowers can bloom on a path of thorns
絶対見逃せない
I definitely won't let it pass me by!
Ah...
もうカッコつけてくしかないじゃん
I've got no choice but to keep acting cool!
そのまま このまま 降り注ぐひかり
Just like that, just like this, the light pours down on us
ねえ 半分なんて思ったことないぜ
Hey, I've never once thought of myself as just "half"!
このまま そのまま 突き進むひかり
Just like this, just like that, the light charges ahead!
La la la...
X.U. / Lyrics: Benjamin, mpi / Music: 澤野弘之
X.U. / Lyrics: Benjamin, mpi / Music: Hiroyuki Sawano
I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame, we were all swept away
Don't take all of the weight, you always do
There will always be something you cannot control
We will overcome, your salvation has begun
No signs, no lights, such a mess all over
Don't kill your hopes
You make me realize who I need
I'll be there, hold on, they'll change you somehow
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn, before you can be turned
Illusions are torn
The fallen angels you run with don't know
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Warm old sepia photographs show
Our fragile precious world, must protect it, respond to the call
Are they really deep inside your head?
Do they control you like a little marionette?
I'll cut the strings off you dead, come in with me
Let me free the wings of your soul, can make it fly
We've been waiting here just to make you whole again
No more hating see, I have always been your friend
No signs, no lights, such a mess all over
Don't kill your hopes
You make me realize who I need
I'll be there, hold on, they'll change you somehow
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn, the shadows appear
Illusions are born
The fallen angels you run with don't know
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Torn old sepia photographs show
Our fragile precious world, must discard it, respond to the call
If you wanna fight with me
Then go ahead and fight with me
'Cause all I wanna do is help you man
You will be the death of me
The power of our army has been cut with a scythe
And if we lose you to them, we may never survive
You can leave, but you must first believe
Just one step at a time, and keep your head up, boy, and you'll be free
Yay!
How was that so far?
That was good! How do you feel?
It was good.
Do you guys like how it's been going so far in the songs?
Yay!
We just had all of our duo songs.
Yeah! Yeah.
And we've also went through the variety part, and...
...and everything, yeah! My foot still hurts!
I don't know how I danced with this foot.
How are you guys?
You're probably fine.
No, no!
You're fine.
I'm not worried about you at all. How about you?
My foot still hurts.
But it's okay!
Yay!
There's a surprise at the end.
But before that...
Oh?
We have an announcement about merchandise!
Check this out!
Woo! Yay!
Yeah! It's the hololive English Promise 2nd Anniversary Celebration merch!
We're releasing merchandise to commemorate our second anniversary!
Let's take turns introducing the merch, shall we?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Oh!
So first up is...
...a Frame Art Board of our wonderful key visual for the Promise 2nd Anniversary!
The frame part uses luxurious sparkling paper, and the printed illustration turns this...
...into a high-quality piece of art. Oh my!
Well, you definitely don't want to miss the chance to add it to your collection or room.
And guess what? You can even hang it on the wall!
Oh my god, on the wall? On the wall!
Next up are the Collection Cards for each of Promise!
These cards feature an attractive design that are foil-stamped on the front...
...and you can choose each card individually, so be sure to collect all of them!
Gotta collect them all! Next!
Next, we also have Ring Necklaces!
This design includes cute references and motifs for each of us.
You can use it as either a ring or a necklace, so feel free to change it up depending on the occasion!
Next!
And next, we have special porcelain tumblers with our designs on them.
It features our talent colors on top of a black base.
They are designed to have a unified look...
...and I bet it'll look so cool if you use several of these tumblers together, like in a drinking party or something.
Okay, last one!
And lastly, we have a 2-Way Tote Bag!
It's a 2-way design that can be used as both a shoulder bag and a tote bag. Ooh, that's actually really cool!
It's even designed to be used as a carry-on bag too, perfect for traveling and convenience!
And to top it off, it has many pockets that will definitely be useful for storing small items...
...like other merch!
Pockets, oh my god!
Yes! And that concludes the Promise 2nd Anniversary merch introduction!
Yay!
And with that, we're finally at the very last part.
Sorry for keeping you guys waiting.
We mentioned that there'd be a special, you know, surprise announcement earlier. Would you like to hear what it is?
Yes! Yeah!
I wonder what it is. But, but before that...
Yeah, yeah, you were saying...
But before we announce it...
...it's time for a stage change!
Stage change?! Oh!
Oh my god, we're floating! We're going up!
Wait wait wait! Oh my god!
We're going down! We're going down!
IRyS, watch out!
No, IRyS is fine!
Okay, okay, okay, we're doing good, we're good!
Oh!
I'm getting claustrophobic!
I'm gonna be sick!
It's open!
I see the light!
Oh my goodness.
Nice...
That's nice.
I feel fresh air.
All righty. Well, ladies, it is time for our final announcement.
Final announcement?
We, Promise, have a new original song!
Finally releasing, it's called Run Back 'Round!
Our brand new... Look at that!
We worked really, really hard on this song,
and it's really cool, really catchy. It's quite different to...
Different genre.
Yeah!
We hope that you guys will listen to it a lot.
The chorus part is quite hype, and honestly, quite easy to remember.
Hopefully it becomes an earworm and you can put it on loop...
Over and over and over again!
That's our big reveal.
Very exciting!
I'm so excited! I'm so excited!
Well, things... well, all that's left is for us to perform our new song!
What?!
We're going to perform it here? Right here?!
Floating here... in the city!
Yeah!
But before we go, do you have any final thoughts about our live? About our anniversary?
I am just super happy we got to do this as Promise,
and, you know, it was a lot of fun singing all those songs with you guys, you know, different duets.
And I just really like the fact that we have a hideout now!
We do! We have a hideout now!
We have a hideout for our celebration.
Catch you at the bar. Yeah!
And isn't this a fabulous location? Imagine how expensive the rent is.
We don't need to pay for it, we don't pay for it, okay?
So, yeah, I'm really happy. How about you guys?
Yeah, I'm just really thankful that, you know, we're still here after two years...
...and, you know, hope everyone continues to support Promise. Thank you, guys!
And here's to many, many more!
Yay!
I can say the same thing. I'm just going to steal everyone's and say that it's been great...
being with all of you for two years and, you know,
now we get to have this cool hideout and...
this awesome song that we get to show everyone! So, yay!
We ready? Yeah, I'm ready. All right.
Let's go!
Ready, set, go! Run Back 'Round!
Run back 'round
Don't stop now...
Run back 'round...
Up with the moonlight, down in the streetlights
Looking for a spotlight, making my move
Whoah, I'm running
Whoah, 行こう
Whoah, let's go!
Days like a whirlwind, don't stop coming
Got me in a tailspin, what can I do?
Whoah, keep running
Whoah, 行こう
Whoah, let's go!
Lost and found, back to where I started
I won't stay down, trust me, I can do it
I live life loud, take it to the limit
So stand up proud, now I'm gonna sing it!
Run back 'round, it's a new beginning
I run back 'round, got to keep believing
I run back 'round, I know where I'm going
I run back 'round, nothing's gonna stop me now!
Woah, oh, oh!
I'm gonna run back 'round
Sparks on the pavement, dreams in the distance
Gotta be relentless, faster than sound
Whoah, keep running
Whoah, 行こう
Whoah, let's go!
Oh yeah...
Lock it and load it, 僕らは explosive
Lock it and load it, we are explosive
Swifter and lighter, 明日もきっと brighter
Swifter and lighter, tomorrow will surely be brighter
Faster than lightning, about to get exciting
Keep on running...
Run back 'round, it's a new beginning,
I run back 'round, got to keep believing,
I run back 'round, I know where I'm going,
I run back 'round, nothing's gonna stop me now!
Woah, oh, oh!
止まらないよ！
I won't stop!
I'm gonna run back 'round!
Woah, oh, oh!
走って、走って、走って
Run, run, run
I'm gonna run back 'round!
Woah, oh, oh!
I'm coming around, I've got a dream just waiting, now
I'm gonna run back 'round!
Woah, oh, oh!
Yeah, everybody, come on!
I'm gonna run back 'round!
Woah, oh, oh!